Hi, this is Sean Hobson, and what we're talking about right now is making sure that our forwards, whether they are the power forward or whether they are the small forward, they've got stay active within the offense.
They've got to be able to move around and follow the ball, know where the ball is all the time.
For one, they're looking to get a shot, for two, they're looking to keep the offense running smoothly.
So what we're going to talk about right now is we're going to use our power forward that is posted up on the block.
He has to make sure that he knows where the ball is right now.
If the ball's on the top of the key, it doesn't do him much good to post up, because we don't want a throw to go from the top of the key to the post unless he's absolutely wide open.
If everybody's dropped off of him, and we can get him the ball, we'll throw it from here, but this is a horrible passing angle to get it to the post.
So, typically, what we want him to do is either he's going to set a screen across, or he's going to flash up to the high post.
Now, if I can't get him the ball in the high post, I'm going to go ahead and move the ball to the wing.
As I move the ball to the wing, then he's going to go and try to post up, because that's the passing angle we want to get it to our post player.
Now, if we can't get him in the post, if he skips the ball across, our post player has to know that.
Then he's going to flash up high to the elbow area, and that's going to give him a limited area to shoot in.
So, what we want to see him do is the post is going to work the bottom of the post; he's going to work the high post area, the elbow, re-post on the other side.
He's got to keep moving, and he's also got to know where the ball is at all times on the court, so that he can get active in the offense, and he can get a shot away.
And that's how to effectively use your forwards in the offense.